William Emmanuel Defty papers, 1868-1927
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
William Emmanuel Defty papers, 1868-1927
MS 272
Defty, William E., 1862-1925
This collection is organized into two subgroups: personal and family papers from 1868 to 1927, most of which date from the late 1880s, and business records from the late 1880s to 1925. Most of the personal and family papers consist of clippings and invitations relating to the Deftys' musical interests, but also include a few family photographs and two diaries.
10.45 linear feet
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections University of Arizona PO Box 210055 Tucson, AZ 85721-0055 Phone: 520-621-6423 Fax: 520-621-9733 URL: http://speccoll.library.arizona.edu/
Restrictions
None.
Biographical Note
From dates entered into his personal diary, it can be established that W.E. Defty was born in England on March 20, 1862. Of Mr. Defty's activities in England, prior to his arrival in the United States, little is mentioned in these papers. Defty emigrated to the United States from England, and arrived in New York City via Liverpool on October 7, 1887. He proceeded by rail to Los Angeles, arriving on October 15, 1887.
In southern California, Defty assisted his father, Henry Defty, and his uncle, Jacob Defty, in the procurement and sale of real estate to English investors, including the purchase of Santa Catalina Island. All of the Deftys were involved in mining activities in the San Bernadino Mountains during the late 1880s and early 1890s. At this time, also, Defty and his wife Ione joined in the social life of the Los Angeles area, participating in various musical performances and events.
In 1890, Defty moved to Gila Bend, Arizona, and worked as engineer on the Gila Bend Canal Co. By 1891, he worked as a mining engineer, geologist and mining consultant, with offices in Phoenix. For the next thirty-five years, Mr. Defty operated this business, specializing in detailed mining reports, the acquisition and sale of small mining properties, the formation of joint-stock mining companies, and the management of mining properties. While the majority of his work was done in Arizona, Defty also inspected properties in Alabama, California, Colorado, Idaho, Montana, Nevada, New Mexico, South Carolina, Jamaica and Mexico.
Between 1890 and 1910, Defty was extensively involved with a series of mining ventures in Sonora, Mexico as a mining engineer, mine broker and mine manager. His most notable tenure in Sonora was as general manager and part-owner of the La Gran Proveedora de Cobre, an American-owned copper mining company with properties in the Altar Mining District.
He died in Los Angeles in July, 1925 after a short illness and was buried in Phoenix.
Organization
This collection is organized into two subgroups:
Subgroup I: Personal and Family Papers, 1868-1927
Subgroup II: Business Records, 1886-1925
Scope and Content Note
This collection is organized into two subgroups: personal and family papers from 1868 to 1927, most of which date from the late 1880s, and business records from the late 1880s to 1925.
Most of the personal and family papers consist of clippings and invitations relating to the Deftys' musical interests, but also include a few family photographs and two diaries. The diary entries generally contain very brief statements of activities for a particular day and can be related to the mining reports and field notebooks by date.
The business records which include correspondence, field notebooks, mining reports, other non-mining business reports and maps and blueprints are the bulk of this collection. These records relate to Defty's business activities which consisted largely of preparing detailed mining reports, commissioned by both individuals and large investment and mining concerns. For the most part, the reports pertain to mining sites in Arizona and Sonora, Mexico, but there are also some other states in the U.S. and countries as far away as Jamaica. Other business records relate to his involvement with several irrigation companies engaged in developing lands for agricultural purposes in Arizona and California. The mining reports can be specifically tied into the field notebooks and the diaries. For a given mining report with a date, the researcher can refer to the same date in a field notebook and diary and find additional information on an individual mine. The field notebooks contain the most detailed information since they have all of the basic field data from which Defty wrote his reports for clients. For a more detailed description of each series, see below.
Arizona-Mexican Copper Company; Ramie industry -- Arizona; Engineering -- Arizona; Irrigation -- Arizona; Mines and mineral resources -- Arizona -- Cochise County; Mines and mineral resources -- Arizona -- Coconino County; Mines and mineral resources -- Arizona -- Gila County; Mines and mineral resources -- Arizona -- Graham County; Mines and mineral resources -- Arizona -- Maricopa County; Mines and mineral resources -- Arizona -- Mohave County; Mines and mineral resources -- Arizona -- Pima County; Mines and mineral resources -- Arizona -- Pinal County; Mines and mineral resources -- Arizona -- Santa Cruz County; Mines and mineral resources -- Arizona -- Yavapai County; Mines and mineral resources -- Arizona -- Yuma County; Correspondence; Diaries; Blueprints; Scrapbooks; Reports; Fieldnotes
Container List
- Subgroup I: Personal and Family Papers, 1868-1927
  - Series I: Biographical materials, 1887-1925
    Contains various newspaper clippings relating to W.E. Defty, his father, Henry Defty, his uncle, Jacob Defty, and includes W.E. Defty's professional membership certificates, voting registration, and naturalization papers.
    - Biographical material for Defty, William E. 1887-1925 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Biographical material for Defty, Henry and Jacob. 1887-1890 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Series II: Scrapbooks and photograph albums, 1890-1927
    Contains a scrapbook of programs, invitations, thank-you notes and newspaper clippings mostly relating to the musical activities of the Defty family. The photograph albums contain black-and-white photographs, largely unidentified, of various mining sites probably located primarily in Arizona or Mexico, street and desert scenes in the Southwest and Mexico, people, and a few of family members including the home of an aunt in Paris, France.
    - Scrapbook. 1895-1927 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Defty Family Photograph Albums 1-3. ca. 1890-1915 (Box 1, Folder 4-6)
  - Series III: Diaries, 1868-1925
    Contains primarily a brief daily account of W.E. Defty's personal, travel and business activities. Also contains some birth and death dates of members of the Defty family, although they are identified only by initials. The entries in these diaries are quite brief. The entire train trip from Chicago to Los Angeles in 1887 consists of only a few lines. There also are large gaps in the early years from 1868-1887. The diaries can be correlated to a large extent with events described in Defty's field notebooks, particularly from 1887-1925.
    - Diaries (2). 1868-1910/1910-1925 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Subgroup II: Business Records, 1886-1925
  - Series I: Correspondence, 1887-1910
    Contains 1 folder of general business correspondence received by W.E. Defty, concerning various mining properties he inspected. Contains 8 other folders, divided into correspondence from various individuals, regarding Defty's mining interests, as either an engineer, general manager, part owner, or investment broker.
    Much of this correspondence can be traced to mining activities mostly in Yavapai and Maricopa counties, Arizona. The Gunther business correspondence discusses Defty's involvement with A.P. Gunther as a mining broker, and relates to the Maricopa Copper Mining Company, and several different groups of mining properties including the Gunther properties, the Independence group of mines and the Keystone mines. It also includes correspondence from Evans, another partner who was involved with Gunther in some of these operations.
    Letters received from F.A. Bradley concerned the operations of the Ibex Mine in California.
    The Leigh correspondence contains letters primarily from Leigh, but also from two other partners, Helzard and Jones, and describes a business partnership Defty entered into with these three men, who were engaged in buying, selling, leasing and promoting mines. It also includes letters regarding daily activities at the Maricopa Copper Mining Company properties, where Defty was general manager, and letters relating to the Little Jesse mine, in which Leigh, Defty, Helzard and Jones were all involved in promotion and management activities.
    The Meston correspondence includes letters from Francis and George Meston, investment and securities brokers in Pueblo, Colorado, and Boston, Massachusetts, and was primarily concerned with the operations of the Ozborn Mines near Wickenburg, Arizona, where Defty functioned as the general manager. The Mestons appear to have been the major financial backers of this mining venture.
    The Price correspondence relates primarily to the Maricopa Copper Mining Company and also discussed the Gunther property and the Little Jesse mine.
    The Stewart correspondence contains letters regarding Stewart and Defty's activities as brokers for mining properties, but also contains letters concerning the Vulture Gold Company, where Stewart served as secretary and treasurer and for whom Defty did engineering work. It also refers to the Chicago group of mines and the Gunther property.
    - General Business. 1887-1910 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Bradley, F.A. 1898 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Gunther, A.P. 1899-1902 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Leigh, George. 1898 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Meston, Francis and George. 1899-1902 (Box 2, Folder 5-7)
    - Price, John E. 1899-1901 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Stewart, H.W. 1899-1902 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Series II: Field notebooks, 1886-1925
    Contains 19 field notebooks, concerning his inspection of mines. Includes sketches of shafts, ore values, and geological notes. The notebooks can be specifically correlated with dated individual mining reports for all of the locations Defty examined. These notebooks served as his primary source of information for generating his mining reports. Individual entries may be several pages in length and quite detailed.
    - Field Notebooks. 1886-1925 (Box 2, Folder 10-17)
  - Series III: Mining reports, 1886-1925
    Contains primarily mining reports, but may include company prospectus, assay reports, receipts, photographs, letters, maps and drawings. Some folders may include series of engineer and supplementary reports, other folders may contain only a single handwritten report, or only a letter.
    - Arizona
      - Cochise
        - California - Chiricahua Copper Mining Co. 1905? (Box 3, Folder 1)
        - California - White Marble Placer. 1912 (Box 3, Folder 2)
        - Cochise - Tungsten Properties. 1900 (Box 3, Folder 3)
        - Cochise - Wolframite Claims. 1900 (Box 3, Folder 4)
        - Tombstone - Louise and Randolph Claims. 1920 (Box 3, Folder 5)
        - Tombstone - Old Guard Mine. 1886-1887 (Box 3, Folder 6)
        - Tombstone - Woolery Group/Dumpling. 1920 (Box 3, Folder 7)
        - Cochise - Warren - Copper King Properties. 1901 (Box 3, Folder 8)
      - Coconino
        - Grand Canyon - Highland Mary. 1916 (Box 3, Folder 9)
        - Grand Canyon/Tayasan Copper. 1916 (Box 3, Folder 10)
      - Gila
        - Gila County Claims. No Date (Box 3, Folder 11)
        - Globe - Irene Group. 1914-1925 (Box 3, Folder 12)
      - Graham
        - Lakenan Mines. 1901 (Box 3, Folder 13)
      - Maricopa
        - Camp Creek - Parker Mines. 1910 (Box 3, Folder 14)
        - Cave Creek - Cave Creek Gold Mine. 1914 (Box 3, Folder 15)
        - Cave Creek - Chas Fleming Group. No Date (Box 3, Folder 16)
        - Cave Creek - Lone Star Mining/Golden Reef. 1922 (Box 3, Folder 17)
        - Cave Creek - Mormon Girl. 1910 (Box 3, Folder 18)
        - Ellsworth - Mountain Chief. 1899-1901 (Box 3, Folder 19)
        - Pinal - Gold Field/Mesa Gold Mining. 1913 (Box 3, Folder 20)
        - Magazine - Cram Mountain Claims. 1909 (Box 3, Folder 21)
        - Magazine - Red Rover Mine. 1910 (Box 3, Folder 22)
        - Magazine - Chicago & Arizona Copper & Gold. No Date (Box 3, Folder 23)
        - Maricopa - Independence Group/North Star. 1911-1915 (Box 3, Folder 24)
        - Moore - Cabinet Group. 1923 (Box 3, Folder 25)
        - Moor - Hualapai Copper Co. 1908 (Box 3, Folder 26)
        - Osborne - Arizona Lead Property. 1913 (Box 3, Folder 27)
        - Ozborn - Maricopa Copper Mines/Ozborn Mines. 1899 (Box 3, Folder 28)
        - San Domingo - Lotowana Gold Mine. 1911-1916 (Box 3, Folder 29)
        - Sunflower - McClintock Property. 1908 (Box 3, Folder 30)
        - Sunflower - National Group. 1922 (Box 3, Folder 31)
        - Sunflower - Sunflower Cinnabar. 1914-1916 (Box 3, Folder 32-33)
        - Vulture - Buffalo Group. 1900 (Box 3, Folder 34)
        - Vulture - Vulture Mine. 1901-1916 (Box 3, Folder 35)
        - White Tank - Sterling group. 1910 (Box 3, Folder 36)
        - White Tank - White Tank Mining Claims. 1914 (Box 3, Folder 37)
        - Winifred - Amalagamated Copper. 1921-1922 (Box 3, Folder 38)
        - Arizona Commercial Slate. 1915? (Box 3, Folder 39)
        - Center Street Group/Contest Mine. 1920 (Box 3, Folder 40)
        - U.S. v. Arizona Court Case. 1924 (Box 3, Folder 41)
        - Bismuth Mining Claims. 1903 (Box 3, Folder 42)
      - Mojave
        - Chloride - Arizona Ore Reduction/General Metals. 1916 (Box 3, Folder 43)
        - Chloride - Chloride & Ray Mining Co. 1917 (Box 3, Folder 44)
        - Junction - Antler Gold Mine. 1911 (Box 3, Folder 45)
        - Maynard - Wallapai & Victor Copper. 1917-1920 (Box 3, Folder 46)
        - Peacock - Hackberry Extension Mining. 1918 (Box 3, Folder 47)
        - San Francisco - Katherine Mining Co. 1921 (Box 3, Folder 48)
        - San Francisco - United Western Mining Co. 1915 (Box 3, Folder 49)
        - Weaver - Klondyke Mining Claims. 1915 (Box 3, Folder 50)
        - White Hills Mining & Milling. 1899 (Box 3, Folder 51)
        - Berkley Mine. 1920 (Box 3, Folder 52)
      - Pima
        - Old Hat - Daily Arizona Copper Claims. 1914 (Box 4, Folder 1)
        - Old Hat - Guerin Property. 1920 (Box 4, Folder 2)
        - Old Hat - Keystone Group. 1905 (Box 4, Folder 3)
        - Pima - Azurite Copper Group. 1899 (Box 4, Folder 4)
        - Quijotoa - Arizona & Calumet Copper/Brownell. 1912-1918 (Box 4, Folder 5)
        - Santa Rosa - Middleton Group. 1917 (Box 4, Folder 6)
        - Silverbell - Silverbell. 1901 (Box 4, Folder 7)
        - Twin Buttes - Twin Buttes & Arizona Mining Co. 1917 (Box 4, Folder 8)
      - Pinal
        - Casa Grande - Shamrock. 1911 (Box 4, Folder 9)
        - Casa Grande - Silver Queen. 1922 (Box 4, Folder 10)
        - Growler - Golden Range Mining & Milling. 1924 (Box 4, Folder 11)
        - Mineral Creek - Cash Entry Mining Claims. 1912 (Box 4, Folder 12)
        - Mineral Creek - Ray Copper Mines. 1899 (Box 4, Folder 13)
        - Pioneer - Arizona King. 1902 (Box 4, Folder 14)
        - Pioneer - Maine 1 and 2. 1912-1916 (Box 4, Folder 15)
        - Pioneer - Potts Canyon Mining Co. 1918 (Box 4, Folder 16)
        - Superstition - Young Mines. 1923 (Box 4, Folder 17)
        - Arizona Gypsum Co. 1917 (Box 4, Folder 18)
      - Santa Cruz
        - Harshaw - Patagonia Chief Property. 1907 (Box 4, Folder 19)
        - Harshaw - Red Mountain Group. 1906 (Box 4, Folder 20)
        - Oro Blanco - Gold Rock Consolidated. 1900 (Box 4, Folder 21)
        - Tucson - Charles George/Red Bird. 1902 (Box 4, Folder 22)
        - Nogales Area Mines. 1907 (Box 4, Folder 23)
        - Promontorio Silver Mines. 1906 (Box 4, Folder 24)
      - Yavapai
        - Agua Fria - Baumann Mining Property. 1898 (Box 4, Folder 25)
        - Agua Fria - Little Daisy Group. 1917 (Box 4, Folder 26)
        - Big Bug - big Ledge Copper Co./Henrietta & Butternut Mines. 1916 (Box 4, Folder 27)
        - Big bug - Boone county Mining/Wizard Claim. 1911-1918 (Box 4, Folder 28)
        - Big bug - Galena Mine. 1910? (Box 4, Folder 29)
        - Big Bug - Klondyke/I,X,L Claims. 1900-1910? (Box 4, Folder 30)
        - Big Bug - Little Jesse Group. 1896-1901? (Box 4, Folder 31)
        - Big Bug - Lone Pine, Dewey, Eureka Claims. 1898 (Box 4, Folder 32)
        - Black Canyon - Gold Note Group. 1904 (Box 4, Folder 33)
        - Black Canyon - Manganese Property. 1918 (Box 4, Folder 34)
        - Black Canyon - Mascot Group/Smith Property. 1917 (Box 4, Folder 35)
        - Black Rock - Burson Group. 1900 (Box 4, Folder 36)
        - Black Rock - Elsie Group. 1902 (Box 4, Folder 37)
        - Black Rock - Gold Bug Claim. 1895 (Box 4, Folder 38)
        - Black Rock - Gold Properties. 1901 (Box 4, Folder 39)
        - Gunther Property/Great Scott. 1899-1900 (Box 4, Folder 40)
        - Black Rock - Keystone Mines. 1905 (Box 4, Folder 41)
        - Black Rock - McGowan Group. 1917 (Box 4, Folder 42)
        - Black Rock - Minerva Group. 1909 (Box 4, Folder 43)
        - Black Rock - Oro Grande Gold Mine. 1901-1902 (Box 4, Folder 44)
        - Blue Tank & Buckhorn - Alaric Group. 1901 (Box 4, Folder 45)
        - Blue Tank - Great Northern. No Date (Box 4, Folder 46)
        - Blue Tank - Independence. 1899-1903 (Box 4, Folder 47)
        - Blue Tank - Sweet Sextette. 1902 (Box 4, Folder 48)
        - Castle Creek - Campbell Claims. 1902 (Box 4, Folder 49)
        - Castle Creek - Lehman Gold Property. 1902 (Box 4, Folder 50)
        - Chaparral - New Years Group. 1916 (Box 4, Folder 51)
        - Cherry Creek - Statehood Group. 1914 (Box 4, Folder 52)
        - Congress - Planet Saturn Mining Co. 1905 (Box 4, Folder 53)
        - Congress - Powell Mining Claim. 1904 (Box 4, Folder 54)
        - Congress - Senate Gold Mining Co. 1904 (Box 5, Folder 1)
        - Copper Basin - Arizona Portland Mines. 1916 (Box 5, Folder 2)
        - Eureka - Seven Stars Gold Co. 1892 (Box 5, Folder 3)
        - Groom Creek - Success Group. 1913 (Box 5, Folder 4)
        - Hassayampa - Bodie Group. 1902 (Box 5, Folder 5)
        - Hassayampa - Chicago Group. 1903 (Box 5, Folder 6)
        - Jerome - Jerome Mountain Copper Co. 1919 (Box 5, Folder 7)
        - Martinez - Gold Dollar Group. 1915 (Box 5, Folder 8)
        - Martinez - United Gold Mines/Alaska Mines. 1913-1915 (Box 5, Folder 9-10)
        - Mayer - Big Reef Copper Co. 1919 (Box 5, Folder 11)
        - Peck - Carder Group. 1902 (Box 5, Folder 12)
        - Peck - Gladiator Mine. 1898 (Box 5, Folder 13)
        - Pine Grove - Western Star Gold Property. 1903 (Box 5, Folder 14)
        - Squaw Peak - Squaw Peak Copper Co. 1916 (Box 5, Folder 15)
        - Tip Top - Bar Copper Mining Co. 1917 (Box 5, Folder 16)
        - Tip Top - Buckeye Group. (Box 5, Folder 17)
        - Tip Top - Harris Consolidated Copper. 1913-1915 (Box 5, Folder 18)
        - Verde - Boston-Jerome Mining Co. 1916 (Box 5, Folder 19)
        - Verde - Cleopatra Mining Co. 1911-1916 (Box 5, Folder 20)
        - Verde - Dundee Arizona Copper Co. 1915-1921 (Box 5, Folder 21-27)
        - Verde - Grand Island Mining Co. 1916 (Box 5, Folder 28)
        - Verde - Green Monster Mining Co. 1916 (Box 5, Folder 29)
        - Verde - Jerome Daisy Copper Co. 1915-1916 (Box 5, Folder 30)
        - Verde - Jerome Pacific/Midland-Vale Group. 1916 (Box 5, Folder 31)
        - Verde - Lone Pine Verde Group. 1916 (Box 5, Folder 32)
        - Verde - Pittsburgh Jerome Property. 1916 (Box 5, Folder 33)
        - Verde - Shea Copper Co. 1915 (Box 5, Folder 34)
        - Verde - Sinclair/Lord Caithness Property. 1915 (Box 5, Folder 35)
        - Verde - Sullivan Burke. 1914 (Box 5, Folder 36)
        - Verde - Ventura Hill Mining/Socrates Claim. 1901 (Box 5, Folder 37)
        - Verde - Verde Cobre Mining/Larson Group. 1916-1923 (Box 5, Folder 38)
        - Verde - Verde Combination Copper Co. 1917 (Box 5, Folder 39)
        - Verde - Verde Hub Copper Co. 1917-1918 (Box 5, Folder 40)
        - Walker - Collins Group/Penn Arizona. 1910-1911 (Box 5, Folder 41)
        - Walnut Grove - Pioneer. 1914 (Box 5, Folder 42)
        - Weaver - Alvarado Gold Mine. 1907 (Box 5, Folder 43)
        - Weaver - Sayer Gold Mining Co. 1904 (Box 5, Folder 44)
        - Weaver - Southern Yavapai Gold Mining. 1915? (Box 5, Folder 45)
        - Weaver - Yarnell Property. 1909 (Box 5, Folder 46)
        - White Picacho - Swininger Group. 1901 (Box 5, Folder 47)
        - Colossal Group. 1918 (Box 5, Folder 48)
        - Ideal Mining and Deve. Co. No Date (Box 5, Folder 49)
        - McKinley Mine. 1917 (Box 5, Folder 50)
        - Monica Mine. 1902 (Box 5, Folder 51)
        - Old Boaz Mine. No Date (Box 5, Folder 52)
        - Sunnyside Claim. 1914-1915 (Box 5, Folder 53)
        - Reports on Bumble Bee & Chaparral Districts. No Date (Box 5, Folder 54)
      - Yuma
        - Ellsworth - Carmelita Mining Co. 1917-1919 (Box 5, Folder 55)
        - Ellsworth - Cunningham Pass Group. 1914 (Box 5, Folder 56)
        - Ellsworth - Maid of the Mist Group. 1914 (Box 6, Folder 1)
        - Ellsworth - Socorro Mine. 1900 (Box 6, Folder 2)
        - Ellsworth - Wall Street Group. No Date (Box 6, Folder 3)
        - Hydra - Glorioso Gold and Copper. 1912 (Box 6, Folder 4)
        - Kofa - Hi Henry Mining Claims. 1911 (Box 6, Folder 5)
        - La Paz - Bentley Group. No Date (Box 6, Folder 6)
        - Planet - Iron King Manganese Claims. 1918 (Box 6, Folder 7)
        - Plomosa - Ibex Plomosa. 1907 (Box 6, Folder 8)
        - Plomosa - Swastika Group. 1910 (Box 6, Folder 9)
        - Bondurant Copper Claims. No Date (Box 6, Folder 10)
        - Havlin Deposit. 1918 (Box 6, Folder 11)
        - Martin Property. 1898 (Box 6, Folder 12)
        - Mohawk Mining Claims/Norton Property. 1900? (Box 6, Folder 13)
        - Yuma - General Map. No Date (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Other States
      - Alabama
        - Cherokee - Rock Run Furnace. 1888 (Box 6, Folder 15)
      - California
        - Kern - Red Rock - REd Rock Placer Claims. 1896 (Box 6, Folder 16)
        - Riverside - Ironwood - Arica Group. 1901 (Box 6, Folder 17)
        - Riverside - Stephens Property/Ironchief and Eagle Mountain Iron Deposits. 1901 (Box 6, Folder 18)
        - San Bernadino - Black Metal - Philadelphia Mine. 1890 (Box 6, Folder 19)
        - San Bernadino - Daggott - Gunsight Group. 1889 (Box 6, Folder 20)
        - San Bernadino - Exchequer - Cashier Mines. 1889 (Box 6, Folder 21)
        - San Bernadino - Monumental - Black Metal Mining. 1891 (Box 6, Folder 22)
        - San Diego - Ogilby - Lone Jack Gold Mining. 1890 (Box 6, Folder 23)
        - San Diego - Gold Rock Group. 1890 (Box 6, Folder 24)
        - San Gabriel - San Gabriel - Gold Placer/Roberts Property. 1893 (Box 6, Folder 25)
        - Sierra - Dewey Quartz Mine. 1908 (Box 6, Folder 26)
      - Colorado
        - List of mine oweners in Colorado. No Date (Box 6, Folder 27)
        - Clear Creek - West Comet Group. 1908 (Box 6, Folder 28)
        - Hinsdale - white Cross and Danville Group. 1908 (Box 6, Folder 29)
        - Ouray - Uncompahgre - Bright Diamond Group. 1908 (Box 6, Folder 30)
        - Ouray - Uncompajgre - Moslem and Japan Claims. 1908 (Box 6, Folder 31)
        - Summit - Wellington Mine. 1908 (Box 6, Folder 32)
      - Idaho
        - Kootenai - Suprise - Boulder Creek Property. 1890 (Box 6, Folder 33)
      - Montana
        - Jefferson - Colorado - Angelica Mining. 1920 (Box 6, Folder 34)
        - Jefferson - Colorado - Rose Gold Mine Co. 1904 (Box 6, Folder 35)
      - Nevada
        - Churchill - Great Eastern Group. 1903 (Box 6, Folder 36)
      - New Mexico